Edward J. Quirk Railroad Collection
© 2007 University of Connecticut
Edward J. Quirk Railroad Collection.
undated, 1924-1989.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Quirk, Edward J.
1.95 linear feet.
Edward J. Quirk (1906-1989) worked as a ticket agent for the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad. The collection consists of train passes, railroad memorabilia and photographs gathered by Mr. Quirk.
MSS20060261
Biography
Edward J. Quirk was born in on June 10, 1906, and worked for the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad from the age of 16 until his retirement at age 62. He served as a ticket agent in the New Haven, Connecticut, railroad station and in South Station in Boston, Massachusetts.
Edward J. Quirk died in February 1989.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of train passes, railroad memorabilia and photographs gathered by Mr. Quirk while he was a railroad employee.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to southern New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
New York, New Haven, & Hartford Railroad Company.
Subjects:
Railroads--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Ephemera.
Occupations:
Railroads -- employees.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Isabelle Quirk Acampora in September 2006.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1924-1989
  - Business cards for Edward J. Quirk, undated (Other 1, Folder :1)
  - Metro-North Commuter Railroad and Amtrak life passes, undated (Box 1, Folder :2)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad trip passes, 1924-1963 (Box 1, Folder :3)
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Book of Rules, 1956 (Other 1, Folder :4)
  - Membership cards for railroad organizations and clubs, 1966-1989 (Other 1, Folder :5)
  - Ticket Agent Magazine, 1967 (Other 1, Folder :6)
  - Metro-North Commuter Railroad, New Haven Line schedule, 1983 (Other 1, Folder :7)
- Series II: Memorabilia, undated, 1953
  - Two decks of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad cards in blue felt box, undated (Box 2)
  - Tenth Anniversary, New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Broadway "Show Train" white fan with Atlantic Coast Line pin in white box with coin stamped on top, undated
  - One deck of cards with a New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad logo in a blue and gold decorative box, undated
  - Three packs of matches with New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad logo on cover, undated
  - Two Atlantic Coast Line Railroad ashtrays, "The Florida Special-New York to Miami", undated
  - Two Tenth Anniversary, New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Broadway "Show Train" pink fans in checkered blue and white boxes, undated
  - New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad card deck in red Queen Elizabeth II tin, 1953
- Series III: Photographs, undated, 1940-1971
  - (Box 3)
    - Five men posed in front of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad train, "The Naugatuck,", undated (Other 2006-0261.ph1)
    - Ticket agents at an unidentified train ticket office, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph2)
    - Ticket booths possibly before opening (under construction), undated (Other 2006-0261.ph3)
    - South Station "before" possible opening, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph4)
    - South Station clerical desk "before" possible opening, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph5)
    - Convention gathering, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph6)
    - Two men handing off book, man on left possibly EJQ, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph7)
    - Group gathering of New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad employees, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph8)
    - Two men shaking hands, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph9)
    - Portrait shot of EJQ, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph10)
    - Ticket aisle after renovations, likely prior to 1957, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph11)
    - South Station empty ticket desks, after renovations, likely prior to 1957, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph12)
    - South Station ticket terminal, likely prior to 1957, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph13)
    - Boston Terminal Company before renovations, likely prior to 1957, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph14)
    - Boston Terminal Company before renovations, likely prior to 1957, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph15)
    - Convention dining table, possibly taken June 27, 1967, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph16)
    - New York, New Haven & Hartford train 4023 leaving unidentified station, undated (Other 2006-0261.ph17)
    - Unidentified train at station, 1940 or 1941 (Other 2006-0261.ph18)
    - Group shot of three men, man on right possibly EJQ, 1940 or 1941 (Other 2006-0261.ph19)
    - Group shot of three men at unidentified train station, man on right possibly EJQ, 1940 or 1941 (Other 2006-0261.ph20)
    - Group shot of four men in front of unidentified station, man on right possibly EJQ, 1940 or 1941 (Other 2006-0261.ph21)
    - New Haven Ramblers at New York, New Haven & Hartford Station, man on right possibly EJQ, November 1946 (Other 2006-0261.ph22)
    - Canal Line Trip A.V.S., man on right possibly EJQ, 1947 October (Other 2006-0261.ph23)
    - Group of second graders take first train ride on the Pennsylvania 1593, man on left EJQ, 1952 April 8 (Other 2006-0261.ph24)
    - Handshake with Patrick McGinnis, man on right EJQ, 1955 December 7 (Other 2006-0261.ph25)
    - Boston ticket terminal Company South Station, "After" shot of ticket aisle, 1957 May 28 (Other 2006-0261.ph26)
    - Springfield Fair, 1960 September (Other 2006-0261.ph27)
    - Commemorative handing off of official paperwork, man on right possibly EJQ, 1963 (Other 2006-0261.ph28)
    - Group photo of five men, second from right possibly EJQ, 1963 (Other 2006-0261.ph29)
    - Gathering of people in front of ticket booths, 1966 (Other 2006-0261.ph30)
    - Formal gathering of people in front of ticket booths, 1966 (Other 2006-0261.ph31)
    - Commemorative pinning of EJQ (man in middle), 1966 (Other 2006-0261.ph32)
    - Holy Family Monastery Retreat, 1969 May 17 (Other 2006-0261.ph33)
    - Two copies of formal group gathering, 1971 October 20 (Other 2006-0261.ph34)
    - Unidentified negatives, undated